tipsandtricks-hq.com 2019-06-24

# Privacy Policy - Tips and Tricks HQ

You are here: [Home](https://www.tipsandtricks-hq.com/) / Privacy Policy

Tips and Tricks HQ respects your privacy. At Tips and Tricks HQ, we are aware of the trust you place in us and our responsibility to protect your privacy. Below is a list of the information that Tips and Tricks HQ gathers, how it’s used, and how you can “opt-out”.

Please [contact us](https://support.tipsandtricks-hq.com/contact) if you have questions about our privacy policy.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Contact Forms

If you submit a contact form, the submissions go to the database and is used for customer service purposes only. The form submission data gets deleted periodically. We do not use the information submitted through them for marketing purposes.

### Analytics:

Whenever you request a page through your browser, navigation and click stream data such as:

  * Your IP address
  * Browser and version
  * Operating system
  * Date and time
  * Site from which you came

This information is stored in a log file and/or database. Any search terms that you enter into the Tips and Tricks HQ Site Search are also logged. This information cannot be used to identify specific individuals, and is only used for:

  * Website and system administration
  * Research and development
  * Anonymous user analysis
  * To gather accurate statistics to advertisers in the form of aggregated data

This information is stored on a secure dedicated server.

### Cookies

Cookies are a technology which can be used to provide you with tailored information from a Website. A cookie is an element of data that a Website can send to your browser, and which your browser may then store on your system. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. Doing this will allow you to decide on a case-by-case basis whether to accept cookies or not.

Cookies on this site are used by us, and our ad management system, Cookies are used for:

  * Ad tracking,
  * Affiliate tracking
  * Customization of content (i.e. not repeating pop-up windows)
  * Storing login information
  * Statistical site-traffic analysis

### Contact Details

The email addresses collected via subscriptions to the Tips and Tricks HQ Websites newsletters are not sold, or disclosed to any third parties. These addresses will only be used by our company to send out Tips and Tricks HQ communications (such as, the Tips and Tricks HQ newsletters, plug-in information and updates). You will not receive any mailings you did not request. The email addresses collected at Tips and Tricks HQ are stored on a secure dedicated server.

If you purchase products directly from Tips and Tricks HQ, your contact information and a transaction history will be kept by Tips and Tricks HQ. We may use the contact information to inform you about the status of your order, updates, bug fixes, and to let you know about upcoming Tips and Tricks HQ products.

### What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

If you have questions regarding our privacy policies, or require assistance in opting out of our email lists, please [contact us](https://support.tipsandtricks-hq.com/contact).
